# Michael Jerred

mjerred.com mjerred.work@gmail.com github.com/MikeJerred stackoverflow.com/users/4854046

### Profile

Contract full-stack web developer with 6 years commercial experience building responsive SPA and traditional web applications. I first started coding 15 years ago when I was a kid and it has been a lifelong passion, as a result I am able to pickup new languages and technologies with ease.

## Expertise

- Angular 2-7 (since the beta in late 2015)
- AngularJS (since mid 2015)
- HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, SASS/SCSS/LESS, Javascript, Typescript, JQuery
- ∖ C#, LINQ, Node.js, Express
- SQL, Entity Framework, MongoDB, Neo4j, Apache Solr, ElasticSearch
- Git, Mecurial
- ∨ Windows, Linux
- Agile, TDD, Pair Programming
- N-Tier, Event Sourcing, DDD, CQRS

## Achievements

- Led the development and designed the architecture for a greenfield project. By introducing AngularJS to the company and structuring work so that it could be done in parallel more effectively, there were significant gains in productivity and these methodologies saw continued use in future projects.
- Built a data migration tool to move a large data set from an existing SQL database into a new project using event sourcing and CQRS. I built the tool using Rx to do work asynchronously, so that it ran fast enough to complete within the target window.

## **Projects**

### **XpKit Analytics Library**

2 week contract with Imagination

I built a library to replicate the functionality of the segment io analytics library, but with some adjustments. I built it as an npm package using Typescript, complete with Jasmine unit tests and generated documentation.

#### Wan Li Portfolio Site

2 week project

I built a portfolio site for a UX designer, using Angular to do some interesting animations.

### **Dragon CMS Project**

6 month contract with Centaur Media

I worked on building a large new project built using Domain Driven Design, event sourcing and CQRS. Event messages were sent from the browser to the server via WebSockets, so that multiple users on the site would be able to see each others changes in real time. The front-end was built using Angular 4, and the back-end using C# Web API and SQL Server. My specific role was to build parts of the front and back-end, advise on architectural decisions, and create a tool to perform data migration.

#### LMI Reskin

1 month contract with Centaur Media

I did front-end coding on this cosmetic redesign of an existing site.

### The Lawyer Market Intelligence

Project with Centaur Media

I was the lead developer on this brand new site, which including building a custom CMS. I designed the architecture for the front-end with a combination of AngularJs, LESS and Typescript; and built a skeleton back-end to interface with the database. After this initial phase the other developers joined in and we each worked on separate modules. Using this approach we were able to develop with a high degree of parallelization, and finished the project in a short space of time.

#### **Fashion Monitor**

Project with Centaur Media

I design the front-end architecture similar to above, and we again developed it in a highly modular fashion with many developers working in parallel.

### Celebrity Intelligence

Project with Centaur Media

My main involvement with this site was the creation of a search widget on the home page. It involved some detailed filtering, so to do this fast enough required using Apache Solr to create indices from complex, slow SQL queries.

## **Employment History**

### Linnet Digital

November 2016 - Current

This is my limited company through which I do contract work.

#### Centaur Media

August 2014 – Feburary 2016

My role at Centaur was to write code for various ASP.NET projects, fixing bugs and developing new features on existing sites; as well as creating brand new sites, as part of a team of 6-7 developers. The sites were built using C# for the back-end, with SQL Server for the database and Apache Solr for creating indices. A combination of AngularJs, Bootstrap, Typescript, LESS, jQuery and Knockout were used for the front-end. Mercurial was used for version management.

One of my main achievements was to introduce the AngularJs framework to the team, and use this to create the front-end architecture for two major new projects. These were a great success and the company is now using Angular as a standard for future projects.

**Acturis** 

August 2012 - June 2014

I worked as a junior developer using C#, Moq, SQL, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

## Qualifications

#### 2008 - 2012 MSci. Mathematics and Physics

University of Bristol

#### 2008 UK Physics Olympiad

Gold medal & one of 15 chosen to attend the International Olympiad preparation camp

University of Oxford

#### 2006 - 2008 5x A2 Level, Physics Advanced Extension Award

Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Further Maths, Further Maths Additional The Manchester Grammar School